Serhii Bilous

SENIOR FRONT END ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate Senior Front End Developer with nine years of experience specializing in building UI interfaces. Deep expertise in Front-end software development, web applications designing, and creating user interfaces that match expectations. Over my career, I have done many redesigns with great user reviews and high-performing and easyto-scale development.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Address

West New York, NJ - willing to relocate inside US

CONTACT

- serhiybilouss@gmail.com
- 201-253-3046
- in linkedin.com/in/serhii-bilous/
- github.com/serhiibilous

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Senior Front End Engineer

N-IX / GRAINGER Jun 2021 - Dec 2022

- Worked here as Senior Engineer, helped junior team members get acquaintance projects, and was a mentor for React Js. - Close cooperation with PMs, the Design and Analytics teams, and other engineers to provide fast, high-quality new features. - Updated recommendation logic for products that increase income from many areas of user flow.

Senior Software Engineer

AXDRAFT (AN ONIT COMPANY)

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- Building a new version of our online editor for documents with such features: commenting, editing with approving or rejecting changes, history and converting DOC files to an online version, and saving it again as a DOC file. - Developing logic around applications using technologies: React, Node js, Typescript, MySQL, CSS modules

Senior Software Engineer

DEEM, INC.

Jun 2019 - Nov 2021

- Starting from the beginning, I was an architect for a single-page application from scratch (rebuilt from old SSR) based on React js. Use GraphQL as a way to communicate with the central server. - Collaborated with a design team using a storybook were created a super helpful UI kit with components used in the app. Very useful for new developers and for making any further changes. - Working with the product team to create the best task flow, investigate, and plan new features. A/B testing scenarios and UI to catch the best results and reviews. - Managed small teams during feature releases. Investigating tasks, code review managed task flow, and was responsible for each iteration step.

Software Engineer

TAXES FOR EXPATS (TFX)

Oct 2016 - May 2019

- Mainly focused as a UI developer from the public site. Did two redesigns for the entire application with fantastic user reviews. - The mobile version gives us more than 95 ratings on google. - Created a Mailing template system with more than 300 emails for different purposes (test on all popular mail clients) - Using React, developed separate resources as an employee knowledge base (internal usage).

Software Engineer

RIA.COM Jan 2015 - Oct 2016

- Started work as part of the first Agile team in the company and was responsible for the front-end part of Ukraine's most popular marketplace (cars). Achievements: - Built a custom specialized JS framework using pure Javascript with the Component approach. I redesigned the existing functionality of the project with new, faster, and better technologies.

• Front-End developer

UPWORK Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

- Owned such achievements as Raising talent and top-rated freelancer. - This job teaches how to be independent and proactive cause you are all in one person when you are a freelancer. - Created over 50 websites with the highest ratings and reviews on UpWork and other freelance platforms. - I used UI frameworks like Bootstrap and Foundation to build a custom design and support scalability and support after release. - Using WordPress (and customizing it) as an instrument to provide the best experience for each application: Shop, Blog, magazine, or landing.

EDUCATION

Master's degree - Automation Engineer

UKRAINE - VINNYTSIA NATIONAL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

2008 - 2013

SKILLS

avaScript Type	cript React	Redux	Node JS	Next Js	Jest	REST API	НТ
nit testing	GIT						

PERSONAL SKILLS AND PASSIONS

Strong in finding the best ways to solve problems and making decisions by combining reviews and thoughts.

My rules: you must first think, then do, never stop learning, and be passionate about your actions, and the result will come up.

I am confident in my decisions which are based on collaboration and analysis. And I can take responsibility for what I did.

I am passionate about new ideas that come to me by talking to people, listening carefully, and analyzing, which I am trying to implement. And, of course: fast cars, heavyweights in the gym, and psychology.